A Guide to the Social Science Research Council records, Japanese Studies and Korean Studies, Record Group 3, Series 7 FA1775
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council records, Japanese Studies and Korean Studies, Record Group 3, Series 7
1945-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council
FA1775
27.43 Cubic Feet 71 document boxes: 66 letter size boxes and 5 legal size boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to the RAC from the Social Science Research Council as part of several different accessions between 2016 and 2017. These accessions were ingested as Accession 2016:004, 2016:006, 2016:007, 2016:009, 2016:010, 2016:073, 2017:017, 2017:018, 2017:021, and 2017:023.
Arrangement
Series 7 of Record Group 3 consists of 6 subseries.
Series arrangement is as follows:
Subseries 7.1. Joint Committee on Japanese Studes (JCJS) program files, 1946-1995
Subseries 7.2 Joint Committee on Korean Studies (JCKS) program files, 1945-1995
Subseries 7.3 Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) grant and fellowship awardees, 1984-1990
Subseries 7.4 Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) grant and fellowship declinations and withdrawals, 1968-1996
Subseries 7.5 Joint Committee on Korean Studies (JCKS) grant and fellowship awardees, 1985-1996
Subseries 7.6 Joint Committee on Korean Studies (JCKS) grant and fellowship declinations and withdrawals, 1983-1996
Records pertaining to the Social Science Research Council (SSRC) Japanese Studies and Korean Studies Programs were identified during a survey of various accessions of SSRC material. During processing, materials were arranged into different Japanese Studies and Korean Studies related subseries to reflect the different activities of the SSRC-American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) and the Joint Committee on Korean Studies (JCKS). Additional groupings of records based on the content and purpose of the files were discovered during processing.
Files documenting JCJS and JCKS grant and fellowship applicants have been arranged into their own subseries with distinctions between files where applicants were awarded a grant or fellowship and files where applicants were not reflected in subseries assignments. The grant and fellowship files within Subseries 7.3 through 7.6 have been ordered by the year of the grant or fellowship award.
Remaining files documenting the activities of the JCJS and JCKS are arranged in the JCJS and JCKS program files subseries (Subseries 7.1 and 7.2.) As noted in the series scope and content note, because the JCJS and JCKS were managed by shared SSRC staff and were under the umbrella of the SSRC's programming for East Asia, there is some content overlap between the JCJS and JCKS program files in Subseries 7.1 and 7.2.
Scope and Contents
Series 7 of the Social Science Research Council (SSRC) Record Group 3 contains the files of the SSRC's Japanese Studies and Korean Studies Programs. These programs were focused around the Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) and the Joint Committee on Korean Studies (JCKS) which the SSRC operated with the American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) from 1967 to 1996. Different subseries in the series document the activities of both joint committees.
Management of the JCJS and JCKS were shared by some of the same SSRC staff members, and both committees were part of the SSRC's programming for East Asia. Therefore, some content overlap occurs between the JCJS subseries and the JCKS subseries, and some files pertain to larger concerns of the East Asia program.
A large number of files in the series pertain to individual applicants to the various grant and fellowship programs of the JCJS and JCKS. There are different subseries for applicants who received awards and for applicants who did not. There are gaps for certain award years in the different subseries. The individual grant and fellowship files primarily originate from between the 1980s and the end of the JCJS and JCKS programs in 1996.
The grant and fellowship programs are also discussed in the JCJS and JCKS program files subseries which contain the bulk of the series' content. Other topics discussed within the subseries include committee administration, meetings, and membership, collaboration with other organizations involved in the Japanese Studies and Korean Studies fields, funding and grants for the committees, the committees' Regional Seminar Programs, committee supported research conferences, conference publications, and special points of interest like North Korea.
SSRC program staff who managed and supported the JCJS and JCKS as Staff Associates, Program Assistants, and Program Directors include Mary Bryne McDonnell, Ronald Aqua, Theodore Bestor, Stefan Tanaka, Blair Ruble, Monique Carroll, Yasmine Ergas, Elizabeth O'Brien, Dee Warren, Susan Pharr, Sophie Sa, Sheri Rains, Terry MacDougall, Raquel Ovryn Rivera, and Mimi Kim. They all contributed to the creation and management of the documents in the series.
Common material formats found throughout the series include correspondence, drafts, notes, proposals and application materials, reports, conference papers, meeting agendas, meeting minutes, invoices and other expense records, agreements and contracts, articles, newsletters, and publications.
Biographical / Historical
Established in 1967, the Social Science Reseach Council's Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) strived to organize and initiate research on Japan and advance the Japanese Studies academic field in the United States. The JCJS was the joint work of the SSRC and the American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) and fit into the SSRC's larger programming for East Asia area studies. SSRC closed the JCJS program in 1996.
The JCJS provided various grant and fellowship programs for doctoral and postdoctoral research related to Japanese studies. It also supported a Regional Seminar Program which brought together scholars in various areas around the country who were not near a major Japanese Studies research center and other Japanese Studies research projects, conferences, and publications.
The JCJS collaborated with other organizations interested in Japanese Studies like the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS), the International House of Japan, the Japan Foundation, and the Japan-United States Friendship Commission (JUSFC).
The JCJS and the Joint Committee on Korean Studies (JCKS) were directed by the same SSRC staff.
Biographical / Historical
Established in 1967, the Social Science Research Council's Joint Committee on Korean Studies (JCKS) strived to organize and initiate research on Korea and advance the Korean Studies academic field in the United States. The JCKS was the joint work of the SSRC and the American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) and fit into the SSRC's larger programming for East Asia area studies. SSRC closed the program in 1996.
The JCKS provided various grant and fellowship programs for doctoral and postdoctoral research related to Korean studies. It also supported a Regional Seminar Program which brought together scholars in various areas around the country who were not near a major Korean Studies research center and other Korean Studies research projects, conferences, and publications.
The JCKS collaborated with other organizations interested in Korean Studies like the Korea Foundation and the Korea Reseach Foundation.
The JCKS and the Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) were directed by the same SSRC staff.
Japan; Korea; Korea (South); Korea (North); East Asia; United States; Area studies; Communication in learning and scholarship -- United States; Cross-cultural studies; Social change; Social history; Sociology; Women's studies
- Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) program files, 1946-1995; 1; 14.15 Cubic Feet 36.75 document boxes: 34.75 letter size boxes and 2 legal size boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This subseries documents several aspects of the Social Science Research Council's Joint Committee on Japanese Studies' (JCJS) operations including committee administration and meetings, grant funding for JCJS, collaboration and communication with other organizations focused on Japanese Studies and cross-cultural Japan-United States cross-cultural research, JCJS's place within SSRC research programming, particularly programming for East Asia, planning and decisions for JCJS's grants and fellowship programs, and support for other conferences and research projects.
  Files pertaining to JCJS administration concern committee membership, SSRC staffing support, and committee meetings. Meeting files contain correspondence, agendas, notes, and minutes documenting meeting planning and preparation, proceedings, and follow-up activities.
  Files show that the JCJS received grant funding from organizations like the Ford Foundation, the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), the Japan-United States Friendship Commission (JUSFC), and the Japan Foundation. Records show how JCJS communicated, collaborated, and supported organizations like these as well as other organizations promoting Japanese Studies and Japan-United States cross-cultural research like the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) and the International House of Japan.
  Whereas grant and fellowship files in Subseries 7.3 and 7.4 concern individual applicants, files pertaining to the JCJS grants and fellowship programs in this subseries document planning, funding, and decisions for award years at large.
  Another major area of focus for the JCJS outside of its grants and fellowship programs was the Regional Seminar Program. Files concerning these seminars document their administration and meetings. Additionally, there are files documenting the preparation and proceedings of the various research conferences, projects, and publications the JCJS supported.
  - Japan Center for International Exchange (JCIE), 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) - General correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nitobe Fellowships for Japanese Social Scientists, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Japan-U.S. Conference on Cultural and Educational Interchange (CULCON), 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - International House of Japan, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) - Proposals, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS)/Social Science Research Council (SSRC) agreement and implementation document, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Undergraduate study in Japan survey, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Journal of Japanese Studies proposal, Susan Hanley, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Convention and Contention, Jim White, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Postwar Japan As History, John Dower, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Showa: Emperor and Era, Patricia Steinhoff, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Japanese philosophy conference, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC) 1990 Hawaii Conference, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) funding proposals, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Media and Politics in Japan conference, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) and Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) committee membership - Member terms, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) and Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) committee membership - JCJS Program Assistant search, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) and Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) committee memberships - JCJS search, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) and Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSJP) committee membership - JCJS roster and member C.V.s, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Japan Foundation - Japanese Studies grant coordination meeting, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Possible meeting sites - Council of American Overseas Research Centers (COARC), undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) meeting costs, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Japan outreach - David Featherman Japan trip, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Japan outreach - Mary Bryne McDonnell Japan trip, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1991 Meeting, Chapel Hill, North Carolina (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) grant selection work - Dee Warren, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Japan Regional Seminars Chairs Spring 1991 Meeting, New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Fall 1991 Meeting, Tokyo, Japan - Notes, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Fall 1991 Meeting, Tokyo, Japan - Follow-up (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - CGP Meeting - Notes, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) 1988 Meetings - Minutes and agendas, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 33-36)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Research Planning Grant 1992-1993 - Applications and planning, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Research Planning Grant Spring 1993 - Applications and planning (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Research Planning Grant Spring 1993 - Applications and planning, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Dissertation Write-Up Fellowship 1995-1996 - Checklist, circa 1995 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Japan Foundation Newsletter issues, 1975-1982 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - U.S.-Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Exchange (CULCON) Delegation from Japan meeting, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) statement on basic research, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) statement on basic research, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - U.S.-Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Exchange (CULCON) - General correspondence and related materials, 1971-1981 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) publicity, 1974-1982 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - U.S.-Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Exchange (CULCON), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - U.S.-Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Exchange (CULCON), 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Ford Foundation Grant No. 710-0457 A/B - East Asian Studies, 1971-1980 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Japan Foundation - General correspondence, 1971-1979 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Ford Foundation grant proposal final version - Continued support for SSRC Asia Program, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Ford Foundation narrative and financial reports - SSRC Asia Program, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Ford Foundation Grant No. 680-0171 - Conferences on modern Japan and establishment of Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS), 1968-1977 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Ford Foundation - General correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Ford Foundation grant proposal preliminary - Continued support for SSRC Asia Program, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Ford Foundation - Ford Tokyo, Japan Office and activities in Japan, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Ford Foundation Grant No. 690-0552 - SSRC Asia Program fellowships, 1969-1975 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Ford Foundation grant proposal preliminary - SSRC East Asia Joint Committees, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - International House of Japan - General correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Japan-United States Friendship Commission (JUSFC) Grant No. 82-29 - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Aesthetics Project, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Japan-United States Friendship Commission (JUSFC) Grant No. 82-75 - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) post-doctoral research, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Japan-United States Friendship Commission (JUSFC) Grant No. 83-97 - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) post-doctoral research, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Japan-United States Friendship Commission (JUSFC) Grant No. 78-31 - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) doctoral research, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Japan-United States Friendship Commission (JUSFC) Grant No. 5 as amended - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) collaborative research, 1977-1984 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Japan-United States Friendship Commission (JUSFC) Grant No. 79-54 - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) post-doctoral research, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Ford Foundation - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) finances, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - International House of Japan Fellowship Program - Fellow placement, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) grant proposal - SSRC/American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) International Research Program, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) grant proposal, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Ford Foundation grant proposal - Continued support for SSRC Joint Committees, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Ford Foundation grant proposal - SSRC Joint Committees, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Ford Foundation and National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) - Budget related materials, 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Grant No. RO-24006-76-74 - Supported project on United States occupation of Japan, 1976-1980 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Grant No. RO-24006-76-74 - Supported project on United States occupation of Japan, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Stefan Tanaka memo to Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS), 1987 October 20 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1991 Meeting - Follow-up (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1990 Meeting, Chicago, Illinois - Agenda and draft minutes, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Fall 1990 Meeting, Boston, Massachusetts - Logistics (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Fall 1991 Meeting - Preparation (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1991 Meeting - Follow-up, 1987-1991 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1991 Meeting - Agenda (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Fall 1992 Meeting, Seoul, Korea - Follow-up, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Fall 1990 Meeting - Preparations (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Fall 1990 Meeting - Follow-up, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) staff working file, 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1993 Meeting - Follow-up (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1993 Meeting, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1992 Meeting - Follow-up (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Fall 1993 Meeting, New York City, New York (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) staff search, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Reports, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - SSRC international program restructuring, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - SSRC international program restructuring - International Program Chair responses, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) annual reports, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) committee invitation letter, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Japan Foundation September 1991 Meeting, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Selection Committee correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JSJS) Fall 1991 Meeting, Tokyo, Japan - Preparation (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1991 Meeting (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) - Mary McDonnell memos, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - International Conference: The Pacific War Re-examined, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Grants Subcommittee, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) 1983 meetings, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) - Grants information, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1983 Meeting, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Spring 1983 Meeting, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 108-109)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Southern, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program, 1991-1994 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program meeting, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Payment record, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Requests for funding, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Correspondence with Seminars, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Rocky Mountain and Southwest, 1990 February 6 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - New England, 1985-1995 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Meeting of Chairs correspondence, 1989 December 13 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Midwest, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Southern, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Washington and Southeast, 1990-1995 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - General correspondence, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - Japan Foundation support - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program, circa 1990 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - Japan Foundation grant request - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program - Reports submitted to Japan Foundation, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JCJS) Regional Seminar Program, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 127)